#### Contact

parkerjakejohn127@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/john-jakeparker (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

React.js Angular Node.js

# John Parker

Web Developer at Self Employed

Miami Beach, Florida, United States

### Summary

Hello, I am a Full Stack Developer with about 7 years of professional experience. I specialize in developing websites by coding them from scratch with JavaScript/PHP frameworks such Angular, React, Node.js/Express.js, and Laravel/Codelgniter. Very proactive and consistently deliver to your high standards. Below you will find my set of skills that also take upon building web pages.

- --- Specialties ---
- React, Next.js, Angular, AngularJS, Redux, RxJS
- Node.js/Express.js
- PHP, Laravel, Codelgniter, Symfony, Cake PHP
- AWS Amplify, Lambda, EC2, S3 Bucket, Cloudfront, CloudFormation, Route53, IAM, etc.
- HTML / CSS /JavaScript/Typescript
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Website Responsive
- Customization
- Bug Fixes
- Mobile Responsive
- Help/Consultation

I primarily build websites using MERN/MERN/LAMP stack and have done a variety of projects for both my own clients and as a contractor for other companies. I am goal-oriented, accessible, responsive, responsible, and I always meet my deadlines.

## Experience

Self-employed
Senior Web Developer(MEAN/MERN/AWS)
April 2022 - Present (8 months)

Goodwin Systems LLC - Orange County

#### Senior Software Engineer(MEAN/MERN/AWS) February 2020 - March 2022 (2 years 2 months)

Garden Grove, California, United States

I participated in both front-end and back-end development as a senior full-stack developer. I was able to show off my talents in advanced and modern front-end development using Angular/React framework, large-scale back-end using PHP framework and MySQL, and Clouding & DevOps using AWS.

- Led the development of single page web application which based on Angular as frontend framework and Node.js as server.
- Solely responsible for pages layout and style design for all modules, and implementing all pages by Angular libraries.
- Customized calendar library to implement the calendar view for forecast functionality independently.
- Utilized datatable library to handle mass data injection and pagination which reduced the data loading time by 90%.
- Managed frontend tasks allocation, cooperated with QA team to accomplish testing covered 100% the frontend features.
- Saved 5000 hours of developer time by engineering a fully-automated test suite built on top of Selenium.

# SPINX Digital MEAN/MERN Stack Developer September 2017 - February 2020 (2 years 6 months) Los Angeles, California, United States

Gained a good production level understanding of industry standard code for Front-End React.js development using Redux and man other technologies. Gained a good production level understanding of industry standard code for Back-End Node.js API development, using many technologies such as MongoDB, Mongoose, AWS, and more. I wrote unit tests using Mocha and Chai, API tests using Postman, and browser automation testing using Nightwatch.js running on Selenium.

# Bexel Studio React/Laravel Developer February 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 7 months) Glendale, California, United States

Created a replacement front end e-commerce web app.

It had to utilize existing backend API data and work better than the previous version of the front end.

I was responsible for making a sleek product overview module that closely matched a mockup.

Product overview contains an image gallery with thumbnails that scroll. An expanded image view that shows the image at 1.5x magnification and follows the mouse cursor. The style selection displays the currently selected style and the sale price is shown in red if that style is on sale. The size and quantity checks the SKU inventory. So if there are no product left for a particular size, the size will be hidden. Also the size dropdown will display the quantity left up to 15 max.

Technologies used: React, Nodejs, Express, Axios, HTML5, CSS

Dreamers & Doers®
AngularJS/Laravel Developer
August 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 6 months)
Los Angeles, California, United States

I implemented this JAMstack website for a local client. The design choices are reflective of the client, but I built the project without a CSS framework. This project.

- Engineered a key role in implementing our awesome new front-end experience for AB customers (MPO page) using AngularJS and Spring MVC which is visited by roughly 3000 customers daily.
- Enhanced a payment method "import" feature by upgrading to AngularJS on the UI from jQuery, elegantly removing duplicate API calls, and redundant "model" conversions on the backend there by increasing the run time efficiency about 25%.

### Education

Miami University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (September 2006 - May 2011)